<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hrvoje&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hrvoje&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:58:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.hrvoje.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Circles</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2020/05/drawing-circles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2020/05/drawing-circles/</guid>
      <description>Embedded programming, microcontrollers and FPGAs have always been incredibly appealing to me. Why? Probably because they emphasize things about development and design that I personally believe to be very important - keeping things short, efficient and simple.
Recently, I needed to draw circles with as little code as possible which always get me into the &amp;ldquo;is there a better way&amp;rdquo; mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eagle Has Landed</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/12/the-eagle-has-landed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 11:47:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/12/the-eagle-has-landed/</guid>
      <description>The year was 1984. Apple Macintosh was just introduced, as well as our own shiny new computer called &amp;ldquo;Orao&amp;rdquo; (Eagle). It ended up being chosen as a standard primary school computer in Croatia from 1985 to 1991. For many of us, kids back then, this was one of the first opportunities to ever use a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Ship</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/07/ghost-ship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 15:29:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/07/ghost-ship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been solving some problems on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.checkio.org&#34;&gt;CheckiO&lt;/a&gt;, a really addictive programming site, and stumbled upon a very interesting golf mission. So, you might ask: &amp;ldquo;What are golf missions?!&amp;rdquo;. The idea is to solve the problem using as little code as theoretically possible. Your score is inversely related to code length and transforms a mildly challenging problem into a very addictive one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting missions is called &lt;a href=&#34;www.checkio.org/mission/ghost-detect/&#34;&gt;Ghost Detect&lt;/a&gt;. It might not seem special at first, but it gets tricky as solutions get shorter. The mission goal is to write the shortest possible code to recognize if three consecutive signals sent in binary are of the same length. 11000001100011 is a good signal while 111000100011 is a bad one. There is at least one zero between every group of ones. For each character used (less than 200) you earn 1 point. So, how do we do this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Math</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/01/cookie-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 15:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2015/01/cookie-math/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a very interesting presentation at the last 31C3 conference given by
two very talented security researchers: Shahar Tal and Lior Oppenheim. The
vulnerability they found targets many different routers from various
manufacturers and was, apparently, patched 10 years ago (!) by the software
company who made RomPager, the software in question. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say vendors are
slow in deploying patches, leaving tens of millions of routers vulnerable to
potential remote bricking, turning into botnets or who knows what else. It was
named Misfortune Cookie for a good reason, but what does that have to do with
math?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tic-Tac-Toe in ... MySQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/10/tic-tac-toe-in-...-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 17:25:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/10/tic-tac-toe-in-...-mysql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever attended a boring lecture, you probably know this game by heart. Frequently scribbled on textbook margins and school desks, it&amp;rsquo;s insanely popular and fun to play. Talking to a friend about MySQL made me wonder if such a respectable, high performance database can be misused and tricked into being a gaming platfom. While it isn&amp;rsquo;t likely going to run Quake, maybe a simple game of Tic-Tac-Toe would be just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would anyone do this? Well, making &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qWkUFxItWmU&#34;&gt;floppy drives play The Imperial March&lt;/a&gt; isn’t very useful either, but it’s darn entertaining. MySQL is a powerful tool with strong scripting capabilities and Turing complete as well, so implementing this game in a single player mode is possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My friend&#39;s 2048 version</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/09/my-friends-2048-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 16:37:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/09/my-friends-2048-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I tried implementing a cool game called 2048 in Python and make it as short as possible. Thinking I did a decent job, I challenged a friend to give it a go. Blown away how much shorter it turned out to be, all I can say is - kudos to Veky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple 2048 clone in Python</title>
      <link>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/09/a-simple-2048-clone-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 01:11:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hrvoje.org/2014/09/a-simple-2048-clone-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then a viral game shows up. It is difficult to name a particular quality which makes a game popular, but most people would probably describe it as addictive. 2048 is just that, despite its remarkable simplicity.
Soon, I started wondering how many lines of code would it take to write it and what are the bare essentials of the game, and tried writing my own version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>